# ALKASOOD

UX / UI DESIGNER | alkasood986@gmail.com | +91-9988447533

#### **PROFILE**

Energetic Web designer with 5+ years of experience in Industry. Seeking to enhance design excellence with an Organization of repute preferably in IT industry.

Looking for one chance to explore myself and work hard in Industry again. Developing & Implementing attractive, user friendly and interactive websites and applications.

Able to complete projects efficiently to meet deadlines, as well as create projects that clients not only utilize but also proud of.

Received appreciation award during career in 2014.

Design efficient user interface (front- end) utilizing various web graphics and multimedia applications.

## **SKILLS**

- 1. Word press, Angular
- 2. Shopify Customization
- 3. HTML5 & CSS3
- 4. FIGMA Design tool
- 5. Professional Responsive Designs
- 6. Bootstrap Framework
- 7. Mock-up designs for Web & Apps
- 8. Client Interaction
- 9. Handling Multiple projects
- Team Interaction
   (Output quality, Ensure deliverance)
- 11. Flexible in learning new technology.
- 12. Self-Motivated

## **PORTFOLIO**

https://alkasood.github.io/

## **EDUCATION**

Certification in PCWD (Web Designing) Arena Multimedia, Chandigarh | April 2010 6 months course in web designing

Post- Graduation in Master of Computer Application (MCA)
Lovely Professional University, Jalandhar | May 2009

**Graduation in Bachelor in Computer Science(B.Sc in Computer)**Khalsa College, Amritsar | July 2006

## 12 in Non-Medical

Khalsa College, Amritsar | July 2003

## Matriculation

Dalhousie Hill Top School, Dalhousie | May 2001

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Cube InfoTech, Chandigarh

Sr. UI/UX Designer | August 2020 till now

# **Responsibilities:**

- Implementing User-centered design, mobile optimized sites and mobile apps designing within preset budgets and deadlines.
- Develop UI mockups and prototypes that clearly illustrate how sites function and look like.
- Identify and troubleshoot UX problems (e.g. responsiveness)
- Understanding client needs, requirements, and expectations and devise solutions accordingly.
- Quote discussions with BD team, estimating quote for projects.
- Implementation of new technologies in team
- Developing websites in Shopify.
- Creating responsive websites independently.

# Web World Experts, IT Park, Chandigarh

Team Lead | February 2014 to November 2014

#### Reach Me:

+91 - 99884-47533, +91 - 9988447353

## EMAIL:

<u>alkasood986@gmail.com</u> alkakishore10@gmail.com

#### **STRENGTH**

- 1. Believe in myself
- 2. Dedicated to work
- 3. Hard Working
- Loyal to my work & life
- 5. Logical Thinking
- 6. Strong Work Ethic

## **MY LIFE MANTRA**

"Everything Happens for Reason Either to bring lesson or happiness"

#### **HOBBIES**

Listening Music Reading Devotional Books Watching Movies Playing Badminton

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Husband Name: Ankit Sood Date of Birth: 10.01.1986 Marital Status: Married

Language: English, Hindi, Punjabi

Nationality: Indian

Current Location: Zirakpur, Punjab.

## **Achievements:**

Received Bonus from client twice.

# Responsibilities:

- Implementing projects plans within preset budgets and deadlines.
- Understanding client needs, requirements, and expectations and devise solutions accordingly.
- Client handling to ensure end to end project design phase delivery.
- Quote discussions with BD team, estimating quote for projects.
- Implementation of new technologies in team
- Creating templates of approved website layout
- Training Juniors, Handling Team
- Experienced in creating websites and UI development for handheld devices like Smartphone's (iPhone, Android and Tablets).
- Implementation of Responsive Websites, Designing Apps

# **Project Handled:**

POSSuperStore, TrulyMedicalGetaways, Wisconsin Mattress, QIPoint Omaha Christian Academy, CRHamilton, Carib Med International, Sports Camp Hub ExtensionWax ford Solar, HTLocating, The Cosmopolitan, Vote Versus, Canyon Excavating, Frankenstein, Panama Pet Relocation, Strongpower and many more...

# Cogniter Technology, Chandigarh

Assistant Team Lead | October 2012 to February 2014

## **Achievements**:

Appreciation Award in innovation in new technologies.

# **Projects Handled:**

Nutrition Formulators, Orange County Car Hand Wash, Texas Interiors, Funpuppiz, Cromer, PhillipsSteel, Classified ride, Investment Diamond and many more...

# Cerulean Technology, Bangalore.

Web Designer | June2011 to October 2012

## Responsibilities:

- Responsible for the Design, layout mockups.
- Designing wireframe for website layouts
- Creating HTML Coding
- Creating Mockups, designing assets (Logos, Banners and images), and
- modifying and enhancing photos

Training Technologies to trainee's

# **Projects Handled:**

.2BrightLights, Urbanswipe, MBA Dashborad, Typefocus, Groupbie, CISCO, Pass The Notes, StockAtBottom, iSolicitor, ichild and many more..

# AARYAA & ASSOCIATES, Chandigarh

**Graphic Designer** | April,2010 to May 2011

# **Projects Handled:**

Flower Hill Resorts, Salus Pharmaceuticals, Ashok & Associates, Aaryaa & Associates, Mission Ishita Foundation and many more...

## **DECLARATION:**

I hereby declare that above statement is true to the best of my Knowledge & Belief.

Alka Sood